<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: information | Betta Coding]]></title>
  <link href="http://cbetta.github.com/blog/categories/information/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://cbetta.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-07T22:07:17+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://cbetta.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cristiano Betta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A new blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://cbetta.github.com/blog/2012/04/07/a-new-blog/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-07T15:17:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://cbetta.github.com/blog/2012/04/07/a-new-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been a while since I last blogged, and to be fair I've been kinda busy, but I also was frustrated with my old blog. It was bloated and heavy to load, all mainly due to Wordpress and Site5's shared hosting. Wordpress started as a nice blogging platform but lately it has been pissing me off (more on this), and I realised that running a whole PHP script for pages that barely ever change is stupid.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So here is the new blog. The old one is still available <a href="http://blog.cristianobetta.com/">here</a> as a static HTML archive (hence why it loads so fast).</p>

<p>This new blog is built using <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>, which is a "blog aware static site generator". Basically what it does is convert a whole folder of template files and blog posts written in <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">MarkDown</a> into a whole folder of HTML, CSS, and Javascript. I've been using a few simple frameworks like <a href="http://nanoc.stoneship.org/">Nanoc</a> and <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a> for work and event management recently and I loved the speed. No database and no server side scripting results in super fast load times, combing that with the hosting on <a href="http://pages.github.com">Github</a> (see here to learn how to do this yourself) makes it even faster.</p>

<p>But let's quit talking about the technical details of my blog, or maybe not. I definitely want to share some more techie things here, highlight some of the code I personally write, workflows we use at <a href="http://emberads.com/">EmberAds</a>, and software I love using. Although it's fun to blog about anything at random, I rather make this blog a bit more topical (hence the cheesy title).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
